#### **NAME**

Lawrence Eka

#### PERSONAL DETAIL

Place & Date of Birth: Jakarta, May 24th 1973

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indonesia

#### **ADDRESS**

Perum Citra Garden D5-20

Sidoarjo INDONESIA

Street 39 Compound 100 Villa 1, Khalifa City, Abu Dhabi, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

## **CONTACT**

Phone : +971-50-761-9425

E-mail: lawrence.eka@gmail.com

#### **EDUCATION**

1991 – 1997 INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI SEPULUH NOVEMBER

Degree in Computer Science. GPA 2.95

#### **SKILLS**

Google Go Language

C/C++ Programing Language

Microsoft C# .Net

Go programming Language

RIATest Automated Test environments

Microsoft ASP .Net

Microsoft Visual Basic 6

Microsoft SQL Server 2005

Oracle Report Developer release 6i

Oracle PL/SQL release 9i

Oracle Database release 9i

NoSql document base

Oracle Workflow release 2.6

#### HIGHLIGHTS

Avid programmer with more than 10 years of programming experience, using C++, C#, and Visual Basic

More than 7 years experience involvement in various business process analysis, in both discreet and process areas, and implementing IT solutions.

More than 5 years exposure in project management activities, playing role as either project manager or various positions in project management structure

More than 2 years experience in performing software testing, both manual testing and automated one.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

2013 – Now Global Aerospace Logistics – Abu Dhabi

2016 – Now **Software Engineer** 

Develop the web based application based on user specifications using c# .net 2010, Crystal Report, and Adobe Flex 4.6. The communication between backend and UI portion of the application are using web services, running on Microsoft's Internet Information Services (IIS) and the database utilized is MS SQL Server 2008 R2. The modules I worked on were of Budgeting and Part Maintenance.

# 2013 – 2016 Computer Engineer

Manage QC activities of application deliverable prior to deployment to production environment. Part of this process is establishing automated testing environment. Automated testing is performed by creating test scripts that are executed by RIATest, while the run scheduler and results reports are managed by web application developed using Visual Studio C# 2010.

In addition, take part in peer-review process of he system design prior development phase, to make sure that the design has covered all major aspects and some degree of details.

# 2010 – 2013 PT HM Sampoerna, Tbk. (Surabaya, Indonesia)

Leading cigarette company based in Surabaya, Indonesia.

#### 2012 – 2013 IS Team Leader – SCM & TCM Systems

Managing direct reports who support application portfolio for Supply Chain Management and Tobacco and Clove Management Divisions.

# 2010 – 2012 IS Analyst Operations Systems

Support application portfolio for Operations Division, and to assist the business users by leading IS team in their projects. Involved in project activities as various positions.

Perform business requirement gathering with users to formulate their IT requirements. Validate and align the requirements against IT's long term plans to make sure that the proposed solutions match the overall IT policy and strategy.

Involved in vendor selection process to be contracted for application development required by the business users.

I was involved in the following projects:

# Tobacco and Clove Management – Integrated System (2011-2012) Involved as: IS Team Leader

The deliverables of this project are Geographical Information System (GIS) application to manage the tobacco and clove agronomy information, application to help Leaf Planners perform data mining and what-if analysis on tobacco price, forecasting system to help Clove Buyers in predicting clove price, and a system to help Tobacco Logistic in calculating Average Monthly Usage to maximize warehouse utilization.

#### 1999 – 2013 Philip Morris International (Lausanne, Switzerland)

International cigarette company based in Lausanne, Switzerland.

# 2009 – 2010 IS Analyst – Leaf Systems

Involved in an international project comprising individuals from various nationalities.

# Leaf Analytical and Reporting Service (2009 – 2010) (Short Term Assignment) Involved as: IS System Analyst

The project is to enhance Leaf Management Application to accommodate new requirement from the users. I was involved in defining the user requirement documents. During testing and training stage of the project, I was responsible in managing key business users and IS Technical Developer Team so the testing could be performed as planned and any correction can be made in timely manner.

# 1999 – 2009 PT HM Sampoerna, Tbk. (Surabaya, Indonesia)

Leading cigarette company based in Surabaya, Indonesia.

# 1999 – 2009 Programmer & Analyst

My task was to develop the application and/or to supervise the contracted developer who developed the application in IS-related projects. I was involved in the following projects:

# Material Barcoding System (2007 – 2008)

# **Involved as: Project Manager**

The objective of this project is to establish a mobile system that helps Oracle Process Manufacturing (OPM) in activating lot numbering system for its inventory. The project has been implemented using C# .Net 2.0 on a WiFi devices and applying barcode labels on the inventory.

Another objective of this project is to provide data exchange channel between OPM and Sampoerna Manufacturing Execution System (SMES). The data communication is designed to be performed using XML files and consists of transmitting material movement transaction and production batch from OPM to SMES, and injecting actual production batch information from SMES into SMES. The data injection will be done using appropriate Application Program Interface.

Recent enhancement to this system connects the Finished Goods status from Genesis (QC System) to prevent failed QC check finished goods from being dispatched.

# **Human Resources Information System (2004 – 2005)**

# **Involved as: Business Analyst and System Developer**

Currently, the application has two modules: Sampoerna Performance Development System (SPDS) and Employee Leave Self Service. The SPDS module is used to let employees to entry their plan and achievements and assessing their subordinate's performance, where eligible. This module also has

the feature to maintain and print salary increase and bonus reports.

The second module is used to enable the employees to take personal leave on line. The system will then take care for the approval and verification from the proper persons and maintain the leave quota.

Considering the information maintained in this system, this application is also categorized as having high security profile.

# **Chart of Account Conversion Application (2004)**

# **Involved as: System Developer**

The application was designed to manage Chart Of Account (COA) conversion from six segments COA structure to nine segments within Oracle Financial Application. It is built using oracle PL/SQL.

# Travel Expenses System (2003 – 2004)

# **Involved as: Business Analyst and System Developer**

This application is built to provide users to report their expenses claims to accounting department. The approval of the claims may include several departments and personnel and the application use oracle workflow for managing the approvals. It's a web application developed using Microsoft ASP, while the data is managed in the back-end using Oracle database and PL/SQL release 9i.

# Third Party Operation Production Management (2002 – 2003)

#### **Involved as: Business Analyst**

The application is designed as an "extension" of Oracle Process Manufacturing in term of controlling raw material input and production output. It's meant to run on remote area and, because the only available communication is through intermittent telephone line, the data is periodically synchronized into Oracle Process Manufacturing release 11.0.3. The application is built using Oracle Form Developer release 6i as its user interface, and Oracle database and PL/SQL 9i as its back-end portion.

#### **Budget Upload (2002)**

# **Involved as: Business Analyst and System Developer**

Developed to upload budget entries from a Budget Application into Oracle Financials Application release 11.0.3 through GL interface provided by Oracle Financials. The upload process includes exploding the entries into subsequence journal entries necessary to balance the statement. The application was developed using Oracle PL/SQL release 9i, and the user interface is a web application developed using Oracle Forms.

# **Product Development System (2000 – 2002)**

# **Involved as: Business Analyst and System Developer**

This application is for managing items and their ingredients within Product Development Department. It is a client-server application, and was developed using Microsoft Visual Basic 6.0 as its front end and Microsoft SQL Server 2000 on the back end. In the future, the application is designed to automatically input released items into Oracle Process Manufacturing.

One key feature of this system is that because the information held in it are very sensitive, we took special precaution in prohibiting unauthorized access to the system and its information by encrypting the data and making note on whose PC/laptop is authorized.

# 1998 - 1999 Infoglobal AutOptima (Surabaya, Indonesia)

Software developer company based in Surabaya.

# 1998 – 1999 Inventory Management System for PT PLN (Indonesia's Electricity

Company)

# **Involved as: System Developer**

The project is to develop an inventory management system for *PT Perusahaan Listrik Negara Wilayah Padang*, state owned electric provider operating in Padang. The application was developed using C++ .Net 2.0 and the database was seated in Oracle express database.

#### PERSONAL VENTURE EXPERIENCES

This is my personal venture experiences, either as individual or as a team with my colleagues.

## 2008 Inventory and Accounting System

# **Involved as: System Developer**

The project is to develop a complete inventory and accounting system for a drug store. The application was developed using C# .Net 2.0 and the database was seated in Microsoft SQL Server 2005 express database.

## **2004 – 2005 Banking System**

# **Involved as: System Developer**

The project is to develop a complete banking system for a community credit bank whose branches are located in several cities in East Java. The application was developed using Visual Basic 6 and the database was seated in Oracle 10g database.

# TRAINING COURSES

Microsoft Biztalk 2006

Oracle Process Manufacturing release 11.5.8

Visual Basic training

Short course on Oracle Data-warehousing

Short course on Oracle Workflow 2.6

Oracle Form and Report Developer release 2.0 training.

Project Management Institute's Project Management Body of Knowledge Guideline training.

#### **CERTIFICATION**

Project Management Professional 2003, March 2006

IT Infrastructure Library Foundation version 3, June 2009

## REFERENCE

References will be furnished upon request.

LAWRENCE EKA • Street 39, Compound 100, Villa 1, Khalifa City, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

EMAIL: <u>lawrence.eka@gmail.com</u>